

Full Stack Developer (Tech Lead)

Khairul Azwan Bin Kamarul Ariffin

Bangi, Selangor Age: 35 (Feb. 1986) English / Malay +6010 767 0782 khairulazwan1@gmail.com

Resume

As an entrepreneur and a software developer with over 12 years in the web application development field, my career goal is to participate in building complex web applications with high availability and scalability infrastructure. With a solid technical background, an eye for detail and a self-motivated person, I can switch easily from database design through Back-end architecture to Front-End development and also the middle man between those roles and operations as a DevOps.

I have the ability to motivates team member to become more enthusiast with coding and programming by sharing my vast experience working with various companies and cultures and transforming them from mediocre programmer to a professional developer

CERTIFICATION

- Amazon Web Service
 - AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Alibaba Cloud
 - Operate and Manage a Cloud Server (ACL03)
 - Using Kubernetes to Manage Containers and Cluster Resources (ACL32)
- Oracle Partner Network
 - Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Solutions Engineering

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science

2005 - 2008 : Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM), Pulau Pinang

Matriculation

2004 - 2005 : Kolej Matrikulasi Perlis, Perlis

Experience

04/2020 - Present: Full Stack Developer (Tech Lead) @ Feets Sdn. Bhd.

- Alibaba Cloud: Kubernetes, ECS, Apsara RDS, AliCloud DNS, OSS, NAS
- Develop REST API using Ruby and PostgreSQL
- CI/CD with Gitlab
- Transform the development from Waterfall to Agile
- Lead and guide developers team using Agile Scrum Method
- Acting Scrum Master
- Consult and advice the management on how they can save the cost and boost up the performance of their API server by restructuring the cloud architecture and design
- Save the company MYR 28,000.00 yearly

01/2019 - 03/2020: Senior Software Developer cum DevOps Engineer @ Carsome Sdn. Bhd.

- AWS services administration: Route53, EC2, S3, CodeDeploy, CodeBuild, RDS, CloudWatch, CLoudFront, ELB
- Alibaba Cloud: ECS, Apsara RDS, AliCloud DNS, OSS, NAS
- VCS: Github, Gitlab
- Docker
- Scripting: Shell scripting
- Jira
- DeployHQ, Jenkins
- Team-up to achieve zero-downtime deployment
- Managing 80+ servers in a distributed and highly available critical infrastructure
- Team up with front-end and back-end developers together with the product team to complete the company's products
- Upgrading by replacing all deprecated functions in the codes from Php5 to Php7 and from Codelgniter 2.0 to Codelgniter 3.0
- Work together with the team for the code migration and immerse myself into bug killing tirelessly for several days and nights.
- POC: NodeJs producer with AMQP (Advanced Queueing Message Protocol) using RabbitMQ and NodeJS consumer to send notifications.
- Using PHP, MySQL, NodeJS, RabbitMQ, Codeigniter, Laravel, Javascripts

07/2018 - 11/2018: Full-Stack PHP Developer @ Alpha Supply Chain Group Pte Ltd.

- Designed, developed and maintained Web Application for the company
- Setup multiple UAT servers (AWS AMI, Ubuntu) with PHP environments
- Working together with several developers around the world
- Extracting unstructured words .docx files into a structured data in MySQL
- Managing 10+ servers in installing and deploying pull request from github
- On standby mode more than 18 hours every weekday and sometimes on weekends too
- Using Core PHP, Angular JS, MySQL, MSSQL

02/2018 - 05/2018: Full-Stack PHP Developer @ Everus Sdn Bhd

- Managing and working with PHP developers team in Hyderabad, India
- Managing and working with PHP and NodeJS developers team in Serbia
- Developed RESTful API for our Token to be used as a payment method by leading E-Commerce platforms such as OpenCart, WooCommerce, etc.
- Integrate several APIs with our web app such as mobile reloads, converting multiple currencies to our token realtime rates, flight and hotel bookings prices and details
- Main languages and technologies used: PHP (Laravel/CI), JavaScript, JQuery, NodeJS, MySql, CSS3, HTML5,
- Motivation to quit: Rejected the 18 months bond upon confirmation with the company
- Projects:
 - 1. Everus Coin Payment Gateway Plugins for WooCommerce and OpenCart
 - a. Technologies used: NodeJS, HandleBars.js
 - **b.** REST API Integration: **Coinmarketcap.com**
 - 2. Mobile Prepaid Topup using Everus Coin
 - a. Technologies used: Laravel PHP Framework, JQuery
 - b. REST API Integration: TransferTo.com, coinmarketcap.com, restcountries.eu
 - 3. EverusMall Travels
 - a. Technologies used: OpenCart, PHP, Mysql
 - b. REST API Integration: Sutra.my

- Working with GLC in Perak for the state's event websites and data analysis
- My service cover as a consultant as well as the web developer
- Main languages and technologies used: PHP (Laravel/CI), JavaScript, JQuery, MySql, CSS3, HTML5
- Projects:
 - 1. Websites using wordpress
 - a. https://www.makembun.com
 - b. https://www.perakfestivalofideas.com
 - c. https://www.pangkordialogue.com
 - d. https://www.srinikahomestay.com
 - 2. PangkorDialogue 2017 Registration System
 - a. Technologies used: Codeigniter PHP Framework, JQuery, MySQL, AmCharts

02/2012 - 12/2016: CEO at Ghuraba Solutions Sdn Bhd

- I co-founded a web development company, where I developed many technical and soft-skills: HTML, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Flash, XML, e-Commerce, SEO, Angular, Typescript, Ionic, React, NodeJs and project management.
- We build hybrid mobile apps, web applications, corporate and e-commerce websites
- PNB, JAKIM, Majlis Bandaraya Ipoh and Institut Darul Ridzuan are some of my big clients
- Motivation to guit: Sales dropped and high overhead
- Projects:
 - 1. PerakData
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, JQuery, Mysql, AmCharts, Google Motion Charts
 - 2. Referral Republic Mobile Apps
 - a. NodeJS, Angular 2, Ionic
 - 3. S&P and Loan Management System
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL, JQuery
 - 4. Buatbaju.biz Apparel Project Management System
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL, JQuery
 - 5. Buatbaju.biz Productivity Control System
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL, JQuery
 - 6. Credoz Agent/Stockist and Stock Management System
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL, JQuery
 - 7. Truevest Real Estate Agency Portal
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL, JQuery
 - 8. NPR Real Estate Agency Portal
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL, JQuery

- 9. NPR Real Estate REN Management System
 - a. Laravel PHP Framework, MySQL
- 10. TAFHIM HR Management System
 - a. Codeigniter PHP Framework, MySQL
- 11. And many more

01/2010 - 01/2012: Software Engineer at Jana Atur Sdn Bhd

- The company I work for is an IT contractor company.
- I built my first web application from scratch. With a little knowledge of PHP, I challenged myself to accept the task to lead the job. This is where I found the true joy world of coding
- Here, I learnt the basics of HTML, PHP, MySQL, AutoCAD
- Motivation to quit: The company focused on jobs that supply hardware. Thus, a software guy on site watching over labor workers laying network cables in the middle of the night at a construction site.
- Projects:
 - 1. Ipoh International Run Website
 - a. Joomla (Virtuemart)
 - b. Integrate with iPay88 payment gateway
 - 2. Ipoh International Run Registration System
 - a. Purely hard coded PHP without any framework

10/2008 - 12/2010: IT Support Executive at Educate To Learn (E2L) Sdn Bhd

- This is the first company I worked for and they supply early learning education toys for kindergartens
- I explored Joomla, Wordpress when maintaining the company's web site
- Motivation to quit: Career advancement as a Software Engineer
- Projects: Maintaining website contents